http://www.bruichladdich.com/my-account/data-privacy/

Data Privacy – Bruichladdich Distillery
ABOUT US
LOGIN
HELP?
Privacy policy
Bruichladdich is displaying this privacy statement to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy.
Changes
Overview of the data Processing carried out by Bruichladdich
This Privacy Policy describes the Processing activities carried out by Bruichladdich concerning your Personal Data in connection with your use of Bruichladdich website at www.bruichladdich.com (the “Website”), and dealings with Bruichladdich Distillery Company Limited in general.
Please send your questions, comments and requests regarding this Privacy Policy to our Data Administrator (DA) at the following email address: dataservices@bruichladdich.com
Purposes of the ProcessingLegal basisRecipientsData transfers outside the EEARetention periodControl of legal ageLegal obligation (legal requirement to verify that underage users do not access content promoting alcoholic beverage)Website users, on first entrance to the websiteNoneStored in Cookies on the user’s computer, user has control on retention.Processing of online salesPerformance of contractMail Marketing UK Ltd.NoneUser record 3 months on Mail Marketing Server, Archive records 7 years on Netsuite (ICloud).Creation of a user accountConsentBruichladdich communications and retail departments (Internal)None2 years from last access/use.Authentication of the user who already has an account Legitimate interest of Bruichladdich to enable users to access their user accountBruichladdich communications and retail departments (Internal)None2 years from last access/use.Management of the customer relationship (Generally)Legitimate interest of Bruichladdich to handle its users requestsBruichladdich communications and retail departments (Internal)None2 years from last access/use.Management of the customer relationship (Local Markets)Legitimate interest of Bruichladdich to handle its users requests“Remy Cointreau Group local market Distribution and Brand Teams
Remy Cointreau Group Distribution Chain Partners”Customer enquiries from the United Kingdom to local market as required.2 years from last access/use.Marketing/prospection/communication by mail and phone and electronic for communications relating to similar products to those you have already purchased
Legitimate interest of Bruichladdich to promote its products and to develop its activityBruichladdich communications, retail departments and Private Client Manager (Internal and Salesforce database)None2 years from last access/use.Marketing/prospection/communication by email or text messages (e.g. newsletter sent by email)ConsentBruichladdich communications department (Internal)
Bruichladdich Private Client Manager (Salesforce Database)None2 years from last access/use.Management of Bruichladdich customer database to better know our clients (e.g. age, country of origin, preferences) in order to render our communication, offer, products and services suitable to their needs (Profiling)Legitimate interest of Bruichladdich to adjust its communication and to offer products suitable to its clients’ needs MailChimp
Remy Cointreau Group local market Distribution and Brand Teams (if required)
Salesforce Marketing CloudFrom the United Kingdom to the United States of America
From the United Kingdom to local market as required.2 years from last access/use.Saving of the users credit/debit card details upon customer’s request (cookies)ConsentNot ApplicableNoneTracking of the traffic flow and patterns of travel in connection with the Website to offer you content and services adapted to your interests (cookies)ConsentBruichladdich communications department (Internal)NoneStored in Cookies on the user’s computer, user has control on retention.Analysing your interests and enable Bruichladdich and third-party to offer personalised advertising both on and off this Website (cookies)ConsentNot ApplicableNoneMonitor the performance of the Website and continually improving it (cookies)ConsentBruichladdich communications department (Internal)NoneStored in Cookies on the user’s computer, user has control on retention.Understand the total number of visitors to Bruichladdich Website on an ongoing basis and the types of internet browsers (e.g. Firefox, Chrome or Internet Explorer) and operating systems (e.g. Windows or Mac OS) used by its visitors (cookies)ConsentBruichladdich communications department (Internal)NoneStored in Cookies on the user’s computer, user has control on retention.Enhancement of the user online experience (cookies)Legitimate interest of Bruichladdich to enhance customers’ online experienceBruichladdich communications department (Internal)NoneStored in Cookies on the user’s computer, user has control on retention.Enable and facilitate communication by electronic means (cookies)Legitimate interest of Bruichladdich to enhance customers’ online experienceBruichladdich communications department (Internal)NoneStored in Cookies on the user’s computer, user has control on retention.Provision of a service expressly requested by the user (e.g. storage of shopping cart selected items, storage of delivery addresses, storage of details if it selected the ‘Remember Me’ option) (cookies)
Legitimate interest of Bruichladdich to enhance customers’ online experienceBruichladdich communications and retail departments (Internal)None2 years from last access/use.Protection of the rights, property or safety of Bruichladdich and of users Legitimate interest of Bruichladdich in fraud preventionBruichladdich communications and retail departments (Internal)None2 years from last access/use.
Categories of Personal Data collected
Information you give to Bruichladdich. You may provide information by contacting Bruichladdich via the Website or by email, telephone, social media, signing up for newsletters or by creating an account.
This information notably includes:
your name;
your age;
your email;
your billing address, delivery addresses and phone number;
your credit/debit card details upon user’s request;
your purchases;
any events attended; and/or
your client account data.
Technical usage information. When you visit the Website, Bruichladdich collects the information sent to it by your computer, mobile phone, or other device.
This information notably includes:
your IP address;
device information including identifier, name, and type of operating system;
mobile network information; and
standard web information, such as your browser type and the pages you access on the Website.
Legal basis
As described in the table above, the Processing activities carried out by Bruichladdich are based on (i) legal obligation, (ii) the performance of the sales contract, (iii) Bruichladdich’s legitimate interests, or (iv) your consent.
You cannot object to these Processing activities when they are implemented to meet a legal provision or when they are necessary for the performance of the sales contract.
When the Processing is based on by Bruichladdich’s legitimate interest, you can object to it. For doing so, please refer to Section 8  regarding your rights.
Where the Processing is based on your consent, you can withdraw it at any time by contacting the Bruichladdich Data Administrator at dataservices@bruichladdich.com
Cookies
Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information which are downloaded to your computer or device when you visit a webpage. Cookies are then sent back to the originating webpage on each subsequent visit, or to another webpage that recognises that cookie.
Subject to your consent, Bruichladdich uses cookies to:
track traffic flow and patterns of travel to enable Bruichladdich to you offer you content and services adapted to your interests;
analyse your interests and enabling Bruichladdich and third-party to offer you personalised advertising both on and off this Website;
analyse the performance and the audience of Bruichladdich’s Website, including measuring the total number of visitors to Bruichladdich’s website, the types of internet browsers (e.g. Firefox, Chrome or Internet Explorer) and the operating systems (e.g. Windows or Mac OS) used by visitors.
You have the right to choose whether or not to accept cookies and Bruichladdich explains how you can exercise this right below. However, please note that if you choose to refuse cookies you may not be able to use the full functionality of the Website.
Most browsers allow you to change your cookie settings. These settings will typically be found in the “options” or “preferences” menu of your browser. In order to understand these settings, the following links may be helpful, otherwise you should use the “Help” option in your browser for more details.
Cookie settings in Internet Explorer
Cookie settings in Firefox
Cookie settings in Chrome
Cookie settings in Safari web and iOS.
Bruichladdich also uses cookies, independently from your consent and for its legitimate interest, to enhance your online experience, to:
keep track of the contents of your shopping cart once you have selected an item;
store delivery addresses if the address book is used;
store your details if you select the ‘Remember Me’ option;
prevent pop-ups from appearing unnecessarily (for example, preventing to continually confirm your age via our age-gate); and
enable or facilitate communication by electronic means.
Bruichladdich uses Google Analytics which is a web analytics tool that helps Bruichladdich understand how users engage with the Website. Like many services, Google Analytics uses first-party cookies to track user interactions as in Bruichladdich’s case, where they are used to collect information about how users use the Website. This information is used to compile reports and to help Bruichladdich improves its Website. The reports disclose website trends without identifying individual visitors. You can opt out of Google Analytics without affecting how you visit the Website – for more information on opting out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites you use, visit this Google page.]
You can find more information about cookies and how to manage them at http://www.allaboutcookies.org/.
Recipients
Bruichladdich does not sell, rent or lease your Personal Data to others.
Further, Bruichladdich does not share your Personal Data to others except as described in the above table of this Privacy Policy. These Recipients are the following:
Mail Marketing UK Ltd. located in the United Kingdom and which store your Personal Data in the United Kingdom, for the storage of data relating to customer relationship management and the fulfilment of website sales;
Remy Cointreau Group local market Distribution and Brand Teams, and Group Distribution Chain Partners which may be based outside of the EEA (see below), for progression and fulfilment of local market user enquiries.
MailChimp communication database located in the United States of America and which store your Personal Data in the United States of America, that require the data to select and serve relevant communications and newsletters to you and others; and
Bruichladdich may also share your Personal Data with third parties in the event that Bruichladdich sells any business and/or assets, and that your Personal Data are concerned by this sale.
Bruichladdich will share your Personal Data with law enforcement agencies, public authorities or other organisations if legally required to do so.
Transfer of your Personal Data outside the EEA
Most internal and external Recipients data are located in the United Kingdom, France or in an EEA Member State.
However, certain Personal Data are transferred to or made accessible to subsidiaries and third party companies located in a country outside the EEA which does not ensure a level of protection equivalent to that in force in the EEA.
Similarly, some external Recipients are located in a country outside the EEA or subcontract some of their activities themselves to a processor located in a country outside the EEA that does not provide an adequate level of protection.
In such cases, Bruichladdich guarantees the supervision of such transfers under the conditions provided for by the GDPR. These frames are shown in the following table:
Categories of Personal DataInternal or External RecipientsTransfer outside the EEALegal basis for the transferMarketing dataMailChimp (External)From the United Kingdom to the United StatesPrivacy ShieldCustomer enquiries and marketing data“Remy Cointreau Group local market Distribution and Brand Teams (Internal)
Remy Cointreau Group Distribution Chain Partners (External)”From the EEA to the relevant local market country.Standard contractual clauses between Bruichladdich, Remy Cointreau Group and the Distribution Chain Partners.
If you wish to obtain a copy of these guarantees, you can send your request to the Data Administrator.
Retention
Bruichladdich retains your Personal Data as described in the table above.
After you have terminated your use of the Website, Bruichladdich stores your Personal Data in an aggregated and anonymised format.
Your rights
In certain circumstances, you have rights in relation to the Personal Data Bruichladdich holds about you. The table below sets out an outline of those rights and how to exercise them. Please note that Bruichladdich will require you to verify your identity before responding to any requests to exercise your rights. To exercise any of your rights, please email the Data Administrator at dataservices@bruichladdich.com . Please note that for each of the rights below, Bruichladdich may have valid legal reasons to refuse your request, in such instances Bruichladdich will let you know if that is the case.
RightContentAccessYou have the right to know whether Bruichladdich processes Personal Data about you, and if Bruichladdich does, to access Data Bruichladdich holds about you and certain information about how Bruichladdich uses it and who Bruichladdich shares it with. You can request a copy of these Data. PortabilityYou have the right to receive a subset of the Personal Data you provide Bruichladdich in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and a right to request that Bruichladdich transfers such Personal Data to another party if Bruichladdich processes it on the bases of (i) Bruichladdich’s contract with you or (ii) with your consent and when the processing is carried out by automated means.”Remy Cointreau Group local market Distribution and Brand Teams (Internal)
Remy Cointreau Group Distribution Chain Partners (External)”CorrectionIf you believe that the Personal Data Bruichladdich holds about you are inaccurate or incomplete, you have the right to request its correction or modification.ErasureYou may request that Bruichladdich erases the Personal Data Bruichladdich holds about you in the following circumstances: (i) where you believe it is no longer necessary for Bruichladdich to hold the Personal Data, (ii) Bruichladdich is Processing it on the basis of your consent and you wish to withdraw your consent, (iii) Bruichladdich is Processing your data on the basis of Bruichladdich’s legitimate interest and you object to such Processing, (iv) you no longer wish Bruichladdich to use your data to send you marketing or (v) you believe Bruichladdich is unlawfully Processing your data. Restriction of ProcessingYou have a right to require Bruichladdich to restrict of Processing the Personal Data Bruichladdich holds about you in the following circumstances: (i) if you dispute the accuracy of your Personal Data, (ii) if the Processing is unlawful and you object to its deletion, (iii) if you believe that Bruichladdich no longer needs your Personal Data but that it is still necessary for you to establish, exercise or defend your legal rights or, (iv) if you have objected to Bruichladdich Processing Personal Data Bruichladdich holds about you.ObjectionYou have the right to object to the Processing of the Personal Data Bruichladdich holds about you and Bruichladdich will consider your request. Please provide Bruichladdich with detail as to your reasoning so that Bruichladdich can assess whether there is a compelling overriding interest in Bruichladdich continuing to process such data or Bruichladdich needs to process it in relation to legal claims.Right to give post-mortem instructionsIf you are a French National or residing in France, you have the right under Article 40-1 of the Law No. 78-17 (the French Data Protection Act) to set guidelines regarding the retention, erasure and disclosure of your Personal Data after your death.
Complaints
In the event that you wish to make a complaint about how Bruichladdich processes your Personal Data, please contact Bruichladdich’s Data Administrator in the first instance at the following email address: dataservices@bruichladdich.com . Bruichladdich will endeavour to deal with your request as soon as possible.
If you feel that the level of service or attention you receive by the Data Administrator above is insufficient, you may direct your query at any time to the Remy Cointreau Group Data Protection Officer at the following email address: privacy@remy-cointreau.com
This is without prejudice to your right to launch a claim with the data protection supervisory authority in the European Union country in which you live or work where you think Bruichladdich has infringed data protection laws.
Changes
Any changes Bruichladdich will make to this Privacy Policy in the future will be posted on this page. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to this Privacy Policy.
You are here: Home1 / My Account2 / Data Privacy
Latest News
What’s So Special About Islay Barley?
On the Rocks
Happy Retirement Margaret Shaw!
Was Bruichladdich whisky originally peated?
Casks Casks Casks
Quick linksCONTACT
TRADE
TERMS
PRIVACY
RETURNS
You are here: Home1 / My Account2 / Data Privacy
Latest News
What’s So Special About Islay Barley?
On the Rocks
Happy Retirement Margaret Shaw!
Was Bruichladdich whisky originally peated?
Casks Casks Casks
Quick linksCONTACT
TRADE
TERMS
PRIVACY
RETURNS
©
BRUICHLADDICH DISTILLERY, ISLAY.
FacebookTwitterInstagramYoutube
Scroll to top
Select your age
Due to regulations in your own country of residence, you cannot access this website
By entering you accept the use of cookies to enhance your user experience and collect information on the use of the website. Find out more
Bruichladdich 1988 / 30 years Bourbon cask: ‘the Untouchable’
Please enter your details below if you would like our Distillery Team to contact you with information regarding the price and shipping of this bottle. This information will be stored until your request is fulfilled, in accordance with our Terms and Conditions.
Full Name*
First
Email*
Address*
Shipping CountryAfghanistanAlbaniaAlgeriaAmerican SamoaAndorraAngolaAnguillaAntarcticaAntigua and BarbudaArgentinaArmeniaArubaAustraliaAustriaAzerbaijanBahamasBahrainBangladeshBarbadosBelarusBelgiumBelizeBeninBermudaBhutanBoliviaBonaire, Sint Eustatius and SabaBosnia and HerzegovinaBotswanaBouvet IslandBrazilBritish Indian Ocean TerritoryBrunei DarussalamBulgariaBurkina FasoBurundiCambodiaCameroonCanadaCape VerdeCayman IslandsCentral African RepublicChadChileChinaChristmas IslandCocos IslandsColombiaComorosCongo, Democratic Republic of theCongo, Republic of theCook IslandsCosta RicaCroatiaCubaCuraçaoCyprusCzech RepublicCôte d'IvoireDenmarkDjiboutiDominicaDominican RepublicEcuadorEgyptEl SalvadorEquatorial GuineaEritreaEstoniaEswatini (Swaziland)EthiopiaFalkland IslandsFaroe IslandsFijiFinlandFranceFrench GuianaFrench PolynesiaFrench Southern TerritoriesGabonGambiaGeorgiaGermanyGhanaGibraltarGreeceGreenlandGrenadaGuadeloupeGuamGuatemalaGuernseyGuineaGuinea-BissauGuyanaHaitiHeard and McDonald IslandsHoly SeeHondurasHong KongHungaryIcelandIndiaIndonesiaIranIraqIrelandIsle of ManIsraelItalyJamaicaJapanJerseyJordanKazakhstanKenyaKiribatiKuwaitKyrgyzstanLao People's Democratic RepublicLatviaLebanonLesothoLiberiaLibyaLiechtensteinLithuaniaLuxembourgMacauMacedoniaMadagascarMalawiMalaysiaMaldivesMaliMaltaMarshall IslandsMartiniqueMauritaniaMauritiusMayotteMexicoMicronesiaMoldovaMonacoMongoliaMontenegroMontserratMoroccoMozambiqueMyanmarNamibiaNauruNepalNetherlandsNew CaledoniaNew ZealandNicaraguaNigerNigeriaNiueNorfolk IslandNorth KoreaNorthern Mariana IslandsNorwayOmanPakistanPalauPalestine, State ofPanamaPapua New GuineaParaguayPeruPhilippinesPitcairnPolandPortugalPuerto RicoQatarRomaniaRussiaRwandaRéunionSaint BarthélemySaint HelenaSaint Kitts and NevisSaint LuciaSaint MartinSaint Pierre and MiquelonSaint Vincent and the GrenadinesSamoaSan MarinoSao Tome and PrincipeSaudi ArabiaSenegalSerbiaSeychellesSierra LeoneSingaporeSint MaartenSlovakiaSloveniaSolomon IslandsSomaliaSouth AfricaSouth GeorgiaSouth KoreaSouth SudanSpainSri LankaSudanSurinameSvalbard and Jan Mayen IslandsSwedenSwitzerlandSyriaTaiwanTajikistanTanzaniaThailandTimor-LesteTogoTokelauTongaTrinidad and TobagoTunisiaTurkeyTurkmenistanTurks and Caicos IslandsTuvaluUS Minor Outlying IslandsUgandaUkraineUnited Arab EmiratesUnited KingdomUnited StatesUruguayUzbekistanVanuatuVenezuelaVietnamVirgin Islands, BritishVirgin Islands, U.S.Wallis and FutunaWestern SaharaYemenZambiaZimbabweÅland Islands
Country
CAPTCHAEmailThis field is for validation purposes and should be left unchanged.
Octomore X
02.04.20 | 15:00 & 19:00HR | 1HR 30MINS | The Wapping Project, Wapping Hydraulic Power Station, London. E1W 3ST
Octomore X is another whisky dimension. A parallel universe where the conventional laws of whisky wisdom cease to exist. It will be Islay but as you have never seen before.
Experience The Impossible Equation.
To win a chance to be at our brand new Octomore tasting experience in London, fill in the form below. We’ll contact winners by email.
Full Name*
First
Email*
Preferred time*Select Preferred Time15:0019:00Phone*Consent* I agree to the privacy policy and I'm over the age of 18.*EmailThis field is for validation purposes and should be left unchanged.
*Please note that this event will take place in London. While these exclusive tickets will be gifted to you, all attendees will be responsible for their own transport and accommodation. Entries are open to over 18s only. This information will be stored until your request is fulfilled, in accordance with our Terms and Conditions.
×
The Classic Laddie
Nutritional Information
The figures below state the average representative values per serving giving 10g alcohol, or per standard 25ml measure:
×
WMD – THE STORY OF THE YELLOW SUBMARINE HAS BEEN FULL OF CHARACTER AND CHARACTERS RIGHT FROM THE BEGINNING.
It started with our friend ‘Demolition Dave’ helping Duncan McGillivray and his gang to demolish the old Inverleven distillery – buying up all the old equipment for scrap and loading it onto barges on the Clyde. All so Duncan had some spares to keep Bruichladdich running in the days of No Money.
As this odd flotilla was being towed round the Mull of Kintyre and up to Islay, Laddie MD Mark Reynier received an email from the Defence Threat Reduction Agency (DTRA) in the USA who had been monitoring distillery webcams on the grounds that our processes could have been ‘tweaked’ to produce the dreaded WMD. ‘Weapons of Mass Destruction’.
Never one to allow the opportunity for a good story to pass him by, or to get his beloved distillery in the news, Reynier embellished the tale, which soon grew to involve spies and the CIA and visits by weapons inspectors. All of which made great headline-grabbing copy in the febrile media atmosphere then prevailing around WMD.
One of the stills from Inverleven was dutifully set up outside the old Victorian buildings, and became an iconic sight, with a pair of Duncan’s old wellie boots sticking out of the top to represent those weapons inspectors searching for dangerous chemicals deep in its copper bottomed interior.
A special bottling was commissioned (of course) and dubbed the ‘Whisky of Mass Distinction’ (geddit?) and much hilarity ensued. At least among the Laddies, the rest of the whisky industry having long since given up on the noisily irreverent rebels.
WMDII: A YELLOW SUBMARINE
Things were about to get even more eccentric because, shortly afterwards, Islay fisherman John Baker was heading home to Port Ellen when he spotted something awash in the sea off the bow of his boat. Being a resourceful man, he attached a rope to said object and towed it into the pier where Gordon Currie lifted it out of the water. It proved to be a very beautiful yellow submarine.
Very conveniently, the yellow vessel had ‘Ministry of Defence’ and a telephone number stencilled on it, which was of course immediately called. What happened next was to become the stuff of legend. He was connected to the Royal Navy. “I have found your yellow submarine” said John. “We haven’t lost a yellow submarine” said the Navy. Which was an odd response as the evidence to the contrary was overwhelming.
John and Gordon then loaded the submarine onto a lorry and took it to a secret location in Port Ellen (actually fellow fisherman Harold Hastie’s back garden). The local newspaper was called, then the nationals, and the following day the red-tops were full of pictures of the two friends astride the lethal-looking machine, carrying fishing rods, and asking: “Has anybody lost a yellow submarine?”
Hilarious… unless you were the Royal Navy – who did eventually admit to it being theirs. HMS Blyth, the minesweeper that lost it, eventually came to pick it up, slipping into the pier at dawn to winch it aboard. By that time, Bruichladdich had (of course) commissioned another bottling, WMD2: The Yellow Submarine, and a box of lovely liquid was graciously offered, and accepted by the captain as a goodwill gesture.
×
Islay Barley 2009
Nutritional Information
The figures below state the average representative values per serving giving 10g alcohol, or per standard 25ml measure:
×
Port Charlotte Scottish Barley
Nutritional Information
The figures below state the average representative values per serving giving 10g alcohol, or per standard 25ml measure:
×
Octomore 07.1
Nutritional Information
The figures below state the average representative values per serving giving 10g alcohol, or per standard 25ml measure:
×
